Oleksandr Kryvchenko

QA Automation Tester (JavaScript)

Personal Profile

I am a passionate test automation specialist with both technical and interpersonal skills. With a strong background in web development and practical experience in functional and nonfunctional testing. I am proficient in using testing tools and bug tracking systems. I have a deep understanding of the SDLC and experience working in Agile environments. Additionally, my past job experiences in hospitality and sales have honed my interpersonal and problem-solving skills, as well as my planning and organizational abilities.

Personal Profile

+34 691 328 818

in oleksandr-kryvchenko

github.com/kryvchenko

kryvchenko.com

Skills

Javascript

React Jenkins

HTML/CSS

Node

Git

Webdriver I/O

Cypress

Postman

Jira

Jest

Playwright

SQL Docker

C#

Trainings

TEST AUTOMATION JS "EPAM"

Mentoring Program

MOBILE AUTOMATION

Appium 2.0 And WebdriverIO

SELENIUM WEBDRIVER

Nunit Framework

FRONT-END "SKILLUP"

JavaScript, React

VERSION CONTROL

Git

TEST AUTOMATION "LINKEDIN"

WebdriverIO, Cypress, Playwright

CI/CD "EPAM"

Jenkins

DATABASE TESTING

SQL + Linux

Career History

QA Automation Tester (2023-Present)

Pecode, Ukraine

- · In my current role, I specialize in developing a test automation framework using Typescript.
- · I'm responsible for maintaining the existing framework and ensuring its functionality by leveraging Cucumber.
- I optimize continuous integration pipelines to ensure that our testing processes are efficient and effective.
- · As a member of the team, I collaborate on creating and executing test plans, as well as saving artifacts.
- · Additionally, I manage flaky tests, debug issues, and improve requirements testing.
- Finally, I work closely with developers to resolve tickets and address any issues using an agile mindset.

QA Automation Tester (2022)

Epam Systems, Spain (Internship)

- · Successfully designed and implemented a test automation framework that increased efficiency and reduced manual testing time by 50%.
- Developed and maintained a comprehensive reporting system that allowed stakeholders to track test progress and results in real-time.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop detailed test plans and ensure that all requirements were thoroughly tested.
- Tracked and reported software defects using a Jira, and worked with the development team to resolve them.
- Developed and executed automated API tests using Postman, resulting in improved test coverage and reduced manual effort.
- · Implemented a Continuous Integration (CI/CD) pipeline using Jenkins.
- Used automation frameworks such as WDIO, Selenium, and Cypress to develop and execute automated tests, improving test coverage.
- · Conducted thorough testing of web services to ensure they met functional and performance requirements.
- · Collaborated with developers to integrate tests into the software development process, resulting in improved software quality.

Front-End Developer (2021-2022)

SkillUp Academy, Ukraine (Apprenticeship)

- Preferably used modern JavaScript library React for logic task accomplishment with TypeScript - like good practices.
- · Coded signed-off designs into working web page templates in HTML5, and CSS (LESS/ SASS preprocessors) and then integrated those into content management systems.
- Used mobile-first and pixel-perfect techniques. CSS Grids for building responsive websites with scalability in mind.
- Used React Redux for centralizing the application's state and logic.
- · Used Git versioning for coordinating work among programmers.
- Worked with API calls and submitted requests to the server.
- · Partnered with QA in testing tasks.

Education

Master - Electrical Engineering (2012-2014)

National Aviation University

· Member of the University Management Club

Bachelor - Radio Electronic Devices (2007-2012)

National Aviation University

- · Recipient of full merit based and athletic scholarship
- · Member of the University Management Club